<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <title>Clykainc</title>
    <link href="https://clykainc.net/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://clykainc.net" />
    <updated>2025-11-17T22:49:05-05:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Clay</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://clykainc.net</id>

    <entry>
        <title>2025 São Paulo GP Recap</title>
        <author>
            <name>Clay</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://clykainc.net/gradient-regular-race-weekend-template-2.html"/>
        <id>https://clykainc.net/gradient-regular-race-weekend-template-2.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://clykainc.net/media/posts/11/Copy-of-Copy-of-Hungary-GP-2024.png" medium="image" />

        <updated>2025-11-08T17:14:48-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://clykainc.net/media/posts/11/Copy-of-Copy-of-Hungary-GP-2024.png" alt="" />
                    Listen to this Week's Podcast [Insert Episode] Round 21 of the 2025 Formula 1 season descended upon Interlagos, the famed São Paulo circuit where legends have been forged and titles shattered amid its unforgiving curves and storied straights. As the championship hurtles into the final&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://clykainc.net/media/posts/11/Copy-of-Copy-of-Hungary-GP-2024.png" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <h2 class="nordic-heading">Listen to this Week's Podcast</h2>
<p><span style="color: #b96ad9;">[Insert Episode]</span></p>
<hr class="nordic-line">
<div class="nordic-card dropcap">
<p>Round 21 of the 2025 Formula 1 season descended upon Interlagos, the famed São Paulo circuit where legends have been forged and titles shattered amid its unforgiving curves and storied straights. As the championship hurtles into the final act, every point is a lifeline up and down the grid. This sprint weekend dangles even more on the line: extra battles, extra stakes, and of course extra chaos. And then there's the weather, that cruel wildcard lurking in the tropical skies, ready to unleash torrents that could drown dreams or crown underdogs. From the title contenders locked in a knife-edge duel to the midfield warriors scrapping for defining prize money for next years ambitions, no one escapes unscathed. One slip, one storm, one audacious move, and your entire season could unravel in the Brazilian capital. What unfolds next could redefine destinies... or cement them as "what-ifs" for history to tell.</p>
</div>
<hr class="nordic-line">
<h2 class="nordic-heading">The Narratives</h2>
<div class="spotlight-box">
<h3 style="margin-top: 0; color: var(--nord1);">Lando Norris Leads Driver's Championship</h3>
<p>If you'd asked Lando Norris, back in Zandvoort, sprawled on the sandbanks, watching his teammate and rival stretch the championship lead to a crushing 34 points—whether he'd enter Interlagos clinging to a single-point advantage, he'd have laughed in disbelief. Yet here he is in Brazil, fresh off a masterclass in Mexico City: out-qualifying Oscar Piastri by more than six tenths, then vanishing up the road to dominate the field by over 30 seconds, leading every lap from lights to flag. That ruthless display didn't just hand him the championship lead—it crowned him the favorite to seal the title. And the sharpest sting? His surge has come squarely at the expense of the teammate sharing his garage, the rival who has up until recently looked inmovable for most of the season. While Lando will look to continue his current form of brilliance in Brazil, the Austrialian driver and now runner up in the championship now will attempt to answer back with a stronger weekend, and hopefully a glimmer of the dominance he showed throughout the european leg earlier in the year.</p>
</div>
<hr class="nordic-line">
<div class="spotlight-box-red">
<h3 style="margin-top: 0; color: var(--nord1);">Colapinto Confirmed for 2026 Drive</h3>
<p>“Tumultuous” barely scratches the surface of Franco Colapinto’s 2025 rookie saga. Thrust into the Alpine seat after just six races—replacing Jack Doohan with a blunt ultimatum: deliver or be replaced. A tough ask for any driver vaulted into a new team with little testing and only a handful of races under his belt. It was sink or swim... and he swam. This is the same kid who parachuted into Williams last year, after replacing Logan Sargeant, and instantly lit up the timing screens, earning nods from fans and furtive glances from rival team bosses. When Flavio Briatore seized the reins at Enstone this year, Colapinto was his pick—no debate. The returns inially were grim: whispers of another mid-season axe loomed as he trailed veteran teammate Pierre Gasly by embarrassing margins. Yet week by week, in a car that belonged at the back, the gap shrank. Qualifying deltas tumbled, race pace sharpened, and the rookie began to bite. While Interlagos may not be Buenos Aires, the Argentinian fans are sure to show up this weekend as he looked to continue a gradual progression with a guarantee to be on the grid in 2026.</p>
</div>
<hr class="nordic-line">
<div class="spotlight-box">
<h3 style="margin-top: 0; color: var(--nord1);">Ferrari Retakes P2 in the Constructors</h3>
<p>Charles Leclerc clung to P2 in Mexico City, salvaged by a late Virtual Safety Car that prevent a rampaging Verstappen from claiming the place in the final lap of the race. The single position valuted Ferrari back into second in the constructors standing - edging ahead of a nonexistent Mercedes that weekend, and the one man circus at Red Bull Racing. Yet Ferrari's season had been a fever dream of brilliance and collapse: blistering pace that seems to materialize out of thin air one weekend - I am looking at you Hungary, then evaporated the next, leaving engineers, the drivers, and the Tifosi at large frusterated with more questions than answers. Lewis Hamilton who joined the team in the blockbuster offseason switch has seen his fairytail innaguaral season in scarlett red met with more adversity then he would have imagined. While he has done an honorable job in keeping Leclerc honest as the season has gone on he has yet to piece together a complete weekend in 2025. While it looked like he would be able to do it in Mexico City an unfortunate 10 second penalty saw his chances at a first podium for Ferrari all but disapte through his fingers as he was stringing together his strongest weekend of the season. The team has done just enough to maintain their lead but with the unpredicatibility of Brazil, maybe the Ferrari will surprise us all coming into the weekend.</p>
</div>
<hr class="nordic-line">
<h2 class="nordic-heading">The Track</h2>
<div class="nordic-card">
<p>Insert Track Specifics Here</p>
</div>
<hr class="nordic-line">
<h2 class="nordic-heading">The Sprint</h2>
<div class="nordic-card">
<h3 style="margin-top: 0; color: var(--nord1);">Sprint Qualifying</h3>
<p>Track evolution played a massive role here. On this short circuit, multiple laps per tire set lay down ever more rubber, turning late runs into a high-stakes gamble—risky yet rewarding amid the chaos of 19 rivals battling for position. Carlos Sainz fell victim early. His poorly timed second push in SQ1 came when he needed it most: tires failed to reach optimal temperature, compounded by yielding to cars on their own flyers. Inconsistent grip doomed a lap that had promised much, leaving him stranded outside SQ2. Kimi Antonelli just scraped through—but as we'll see, he'd loom large later. Ferrari looked utterly adrift, both drivers grappling all session. SQ2 proved brutal, especially in sector two around Turn 10. Leclerc spun in the dying moments, triggering a yellow flag as Hamilton trailed right behind. Leclerc's earlier banker held just enough buffer for a squeak into SQ3; Hamilton, unable to improve, was eliminated. The SF-25 appeared miserable. They'd need Saturday's sprint qualifying to atone after Friday's woes—exacerbated by a bold FP1 gamble on high-fuel hards that yielded scant usable data. In that same SQ2, Fernando Alonso stunned with a blistering first push on fresh mediums, claiming P1—the Spaniard's first such feat in a qualifying segment since 2017. The lap proved untouchable; no one bettered it thereafter. Lance Stroll flew under the radar but strung together tidy laps for P7 and a spot in SQ3. Alonso carried the momentum into the top-10 shootout, securing P5. SQ3 boiled down to one flawless lap. Oscar Piastri, strong in FP1, suffered understeer into Turn 1 that cost ~0.3s overall versus teammate Lando Norris. A minor gain still netted P3, ahead of George Russell who couldn't improve on his second attempt. The shock? Antonelli's opener—good for P2, outqualifying Russell for the second straight weekend. His time held firm, earning a front-row start alongside pole-sitter Norris. Lando's solid first flyer improved further on the second, padding his margin. Now he must defend pole from McLaren teammate Piastri lurking right behind.Beyond Antonelli’s heroics, the real SQ3 bombshell was Red Bull’s collapse—especially Verstappen’s. Max ran just one lap on softs, theoretically armed with the day’s richest tire data after rivals skipped them in FP1. Yet he bled over three tenths in sector two’s flowing corners alone, hopelessly off the McLaren pace. Red Bull’s contrarian FP1 plan—hards first, then a single softs flyer—banked on Verstappen’s one-lap witchcraft. It backfired. P6 was the damage, sandwiched between both McLarens and Alonso. Mercedes, by contrast, looked genuinely frisky up front. Russell and Antonelli mixed it with the orange cars, hinting at a setup dialed for dry qualifying. Whether that holds in Saturday’s likely wet sprint—or Sunday’s grand prix—remains the great unknown. Every frontrunner faces the same gamble: Friday’s pecking order could evaporate under rain. That’s the beauty, and brutality, of sprint weekends.</p>
<div class="nordic-quote">
<blockquote>
<p>It was a little bit tougher than I would have liked, close between lots of cars – Mercedes were quick on the softs. But we did the job we needed to do. Quali around here is tricky - but it is fun, it always puts a smile on your face.</p>
</blockquote>
<div class="author">Lando Norris</div>
</div>
<hr class="nordic-line">
<h3 style="margin-top: 0; color: var(--nord1);">The Sprint Race</h3>
<p>As the cars lined up on their blocks in preparation for the 24-lap showdown, the track remained glossy with dampness, puddles decorating the surface. The inside drivers in the top six—Lando, Oscar, and Fernando—all started on the yellow medium C3 tires. The outside positions of Kimi, George, and Max, conversely, opted for the red C4 soft tires. Heading into turn one off the start, Lando secured the drier outside line, while Kimi held P2, defending against Piastri, who was forced to roll wider off the ideal line due to Antonelli. The field progressed through turns 2 and 3, where Max quickly dispatched Fernando Alonso, whose mediums struggled to reach an optimal temperature window, advancing to P5. Down the straight toward turn 4 on lap 1, Liam was forced onto the grass on the inside while battling wheel-to-wheel with Oliver Bearman. The two made contact ahead of the apex, sending Bearman pirouetting down the order. Out front, Lando in clean air began building momentum, pulling ahead of Antonelli by over 1.4 seconds. Confidently navigating the Senna Esses in turns 2 and 3, Lando took more kerb on lap 6 as water sprayed up from the newly resurfaced asphalt onto the white painted line. Antonelli, hyper-aware of the water kicked up at the apex, cautiously avoided the kerb entirely. Unfortunately, Oscar—unable to see the hazard and pushing to close on Antonelli—entered the same turn on the kerb; as his wheel dipped onto the white painted line for an instant, with throttle unsettled, the front and rear snapped, sending Piastri into the barrier at turn 3 and ending his Sprint race—a crucial blow in the Drivers' Championship battle he was immersed in. Oscar wasn't alone in finding the wall that lap: both Nico Hulkenberg and Franco Colapinto were similarly caught out by the white line, ending up in the same barrier. The session entered a Red Flag period. Hulkenberg managed to limp back to the pit lane, and with FIA oversight, he was permitted repairs to both front and rear, allowing him to continue. After a lengthy delay to clear debris and repair barriers, the race resumed with a rolling start rather than a standing one. Teams swapped tires during the red flag: those on mediums switched to softs, and those on softs to mediums. Following the formation lap for the rolling restart, Lando Norris got a strong jump on the slow-throttle Antonelli, who came under immediate pressure from George Russell heading into the Esses of turns 1, 2, and 3. Antonelli held off his senior teammate, enabling Lando to extend his lead to +1.4 seconds over the Italian.However, the rookie refused to let Lando disappear into the sunset. As the soft tires on Norris’s McLaren began to grain and fall off the cliff in the closing laps, Antonelli’s mediums finally came alive. The Italian hunted Lando down, reeling him into DRS range and closing to within +0.6 seconds by lap 21. Yet the outside line into turn 1 proved too greedy a gamble; Norris calmly managed the early delta he’d banked, crossing the line in P1 with Antonelli a hard-fought P2.Further back, Leclerc finally pried his way past Alonso after shadowing the Aston Martin’s gearbox for most of the race. Gasly, electric all weekend in an otherwise woeful Alpine, pounced on a fading Lance Stroll to vault into the points—his first top-ten finish since Silverstone earlier in the year. A heart-stopping finale unfolded on the last lap: Bortoleto, DRS open in pursuit of Albon, lost the rear mid-overtake and speared into the inside wall on the start-finish straight. The Sauber ricocheted across the track and slammed driver-side-on into the turn 1 barrier at 57 g. The car was obliterated; any hope of rebuilding it before qualifying looked bleak. Miraculously, the hometown rookie climbed out unscathed—a ringing testament to modern F1 safety standards.Mercedes reclaimed P2 in the constructors’ standings, while Norris extended his championship lead over his stricken teammate by 9 points following Piastri’s DNF. In the post-race pen, Lando warned that Mercedes’ race pace was “seriously strong” and not to sleep on them for qualifying or the Grand Prix. Oscar, meanwhile, vowed to park the disappointment and reset for the evening session ahead.</p>
</div>
<hr class="nordic-line">
<h2 class="nordic-heading">The Race</h2>
<div class="nordic-card">
<h3 style="margin-top: 0; color: var(--nord1);">Race Qualifying</h3>
<p>The weather had flipped: sunny, hotter, bone-dry, and gusty. Track evolution was supposed to spike through Saturday evening, but the sun baked the surface and pulled fresh oils to the top—grip went backward instead of forward. Front-runners struggled early. Max immediately lost the rear in sector 2, oversteering wide through turn 9 and falling to the back foot in Q1. The man who’d never been knocked out on merit in his career suffered the shock elimination of the session: unable to improve, he missed Q2 cut-off. His first-ever Q1 exit on pure pace—previous rear-grid starts had always been power-unit penalties. Max wasn’t alone in the second sector; both Ferraris danced on ice through turn 8, tails stepping out lap after lap. In the Sauber garage, Gabriel Bortoleto—still shaken from his horrifying sprint-ending crash—was a non-starter for qualifying. The mechanics, however, performed heroics: they rebuilt the spare chassis, gearbox, and every electrical and mechanical system in the nick of time before the session closed. Confirmation that the hometown rookie would indeed take the grid for his first Brazilian Grand Prix. As the home crowd and the V.I.Ps in his garage erupted with cheers and applauds. Highlights early on was the continued form from Pierre Gasly and the excellent pace of Oliver Bearman who was over +0.5 seconds from his teammate Estaban Ocon as Lando topped the first session.Into Q2, Ferrari’s woes persisted. Another violent oversteer snap forced Leclerc to abort his first push lap, lifting off the throttle mid-corner. Meanwhile, Bearman—absolutely on fire—blazed to the top of the timesheets on his opening flyer, leaving the field stunned as the first runs concluded. Leclerc rejoined on the same softs, scraping together a time but now under intense pressure to deliver on his final flyer. Hamilton, teetering in P10, was in equally dire straits. As teams stacked in the pit lane for the decisive runs, the air crackled with uncertainty—front-runners looked vulnerable, and chaos loomed. In the dying moments, Leclerc’s earlier banker proved just enough. A late yellow flag triggered by a spin elsewhere left him safe above the cut line. Hamilton, however, could not summon the lap. Buried under the weight of a tragic weekend—noise, flags, pressure—he crossed the line in P13, eliminated. A crushing blow for a seven-time champion still wrestling the unpredictable SF-25. Nico Hülkenberg, quietly stitching together a strong weekend, found himself in rarefied air: the RB duo and Pierre Gasly capitalized on the carnage to sneak into the top ten shootout. Oliver Bearman, just two tenths shy of Lando Norris when the Q2 clock hit zero, sat primed to carry his momentum into the final ten minutes—if he could repeat the magic, a front-row shock was on the cards. In the top-10 shootout, Lando’s first push lap unraveled with a lock-up into turn 1, bleeding over six tenths and erasing the near-perfection he’d shown all weekend. One shot remained to claw back pole as he was on the backfoot to start the second runs. Antonelli looked rapid early, but a ragged middle sector kept provisional pole out of reach. Piastri seized P1 as the final flyers began but that would be short lived as the phenomenal weeked for Lando continued. Under crushing pressure, Norris delivered: his single lap edged closest rival Kimi Antonelli, whose improved second run still fell short. Leclerc who has made a career of being a master of the one-lap pace conjured a surprisingly, unsurprisingly P3, demoting McLaren's Oscar Piastri to the second row. George Russell, baffled by persistent braking woes, gambled on mediums for a second stint but found nothing; he settled for P6, the RB of Isack Hadjar slotting ahead in P5.</p>
<hr class="nordic-line">
<h3 style="margin-top: 0; color: var(--nord1);">The Feature Race</h3>
<p>Prerace we got word from the FIA that Max had in fact elected to take a fresh power unit and make setup changes outside parc fermé, condemning him to a pit-lane start. Ocon followed suit and joined him at the back. With clear skies overhead, the paddock buzzed: could Max repeat last year’s wet-weather miracle from P17 to P1? The only hitch—no safety car was guaranteed if the racing stayed clean. Lights out. The field crested the rise and dove into turn 1. Antonelli, alone among the top four, started on softs. Chaos erupted immediately: Hamilton, from P13, tangled with Sainz at the apex and tumbled to the rear. Moments later, a safety car was deployed—Gabriel Bortoleto, already enduring a nightmare home debut, clipped the turn-7 barrier bringing out the saftey car. The marshalls worked dilligently to clean up the crash as the race resumed on Lap 6. On the restart, Lando leading the pack got a brilliant jump into the first corner. Piastri and Leclerc pounced on Antonelli, the trio going three-wide into the Senna S. Oscar, squeezed to the inside, locked up trying to avoid the Mercedes in the middle. Contact. Antonelli’s car snapped right, rear-ending Leclerc on the outside.The Ferrari’s left-front tire tore clean off; terminal damage forced immediate retirement. Scuderia’s weekend spiraled from bad to catastrophic. Earlier, Hamilton had speared the Alpine of Franco Colapinto down the main straight; his own floor and front wing shattered, spraying carbon fiber across the asphalt. Max, already slicing to P13 on the inferior hards, unfortunately came into contact with the debris field—both right-side tires punctured forcing the team to to pit for mediums, his charge stalled just as momentum was building.  By lap 12, George Russell dispatched the RB of Isack Hadjar, who’d inherited P4 amid the Leclerc-Piastri carnage. Oscar, now looming behind his teammate with a penalty hanging over him, kept the pressure on. Midfield mayhem escalated: Yuki Tsunoda, already enduring a nightmare, locked up and punted another car, earning the first of several penalties. Meanwhile, Oliver Bearman’s sensational weekend continued; he surged to P6 with a daring lunge past Lawson into the Senna S.Then came Max—relentless, slicing through the field like a hot knife. From the pit lane, he’d already carved into the top ten and was closing on at least a top 6 finish in the points when the stewards suddently dropped the hammer: a gut-wrenching 10-second penalty for Piastri. Served in the pits, it all but erased his podium hopes.Lap 22: the leaders blinked. Antonelli pitted first, desperate to cover Piastri (who still had to serve his 10) and the charging Bearman on fresher rubber. At Interlagos, a clean stop costs ~20 seconds—strategy now hinged on execution and survival. With Max closing in on Oscar Piastri, the McLaren driver had to make a decision, either pit or try and go as long as he could and try and stay ahead so he could pit on fresher slicks and chase down Verstappen. But it wasn't just Oscar's strategy that was on the line. Drivers debating on the go long strategy with the single stop or do a 2 stop strategy. Verstappen who was lapping over half a second faster than Russell meant the pressure was on for all the front runners, make the call or die by your decisions. On Lap 32 Lando made his first pit to softs and comes out behind Max Verstappen. The crowd and myself held our breath as Lando would have to make the pass to Max on track - a feat that had been a challenge for Lando throughout his 2024 campaign but he is able to do so on Lap 35 which is crucial not just for him and his champiosnhip fight, but the lifeline on his soft tires. Max is just 33 seconds from the leader. </p>
</div>
<hr class="nordic-line">
<h2 class="nordic-heading">The Post Race Landscape</h2>
<div class="nordic-card">
<h3 style="margin-top: 0; color: var(--nord1);">Landscape Title</h3>
<p>Insert Information and Stats and Standings after the weekend</p>
<hr class="nordic-line">
<h3 style="margin-top: 0; color: var(--nord1);">Final Thoughts</h3>
<p>Insert Final Thoughts Here</p>
</div>
<hr class="nordic-line">
<h2 class="nordic-heading">The Extras</h2>
<div class="spotlight-box-red">
<h3 style="margin-top: 0; color: var(--nord1);">Extra Story 1</h3>
<p>Insert Extra Story Here</p>
</div>
<hr class="nordic-line">
<div class="spotlight-box">
<h3 style="margin-top: 0; color: var(--nord1);">Extra Story 2</h3>
<p>Write Narrative Here</p>
</div>
<hr class="nordic-line">
<div class="spotlight-box-red">
<h3 style="margin-top: 0; color: var(--nord1);">Extra Story 3</h3>
<p>Insert Extra Story Here</p>
</div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Mexico City GP 2025</title>
        <author>
            <name>Clay</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://clykainc.net/test.html"/>
        <id>https://clykainc.net/test.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://clykainc.net/media/posts/6/Mexico-GP.png" medium="image" />
            <category term="Gradient"/>

        <updated>2025-10-28T08:21:11-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://clykainc.net/media/posts/6/Mexico-GP.png" alt="" />
                    Listen to the Podcast Round 20 of the 2025 F1 season took us inside to The Autodromo Hermanos Rodriquez for the Grand Prix's 10th Anniversary as the season makes way for the final 5 tracks of year. With a driver's championship battle still up for&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://clykainc.net/media/posts/6/Mexico-GP.png" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <h2 class="nordic-heading">Listen to the Podcast </h2>
<div class="post__iframe"><iframe width="700" height="352" style="border-radius: 12px;" data-testid="embed-iframe" src="https://open.spotify.com/embed/episode/7J2kq4kIgKMumSkVwNn4yo?utm_source=generator&amp;t=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" allow="autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; fullscreen; picture-in-picture" loading="lazy"></iframe></div>
<hr class="nordic-line">
<div class="nordic-card dropcap">
<p>Round 20 of the 2025 F1 season took us inside to The Autodromo Hermanos Rodriquez for the Grand Prix's 10th Anniversary as the season makes way for the final 5 tracks of year. With a driver's championship battle still up for grabs, teams up and down the paddock ffighting for millions of dollars in prize money and some drivers racing to just stay on the grid in 2026. Lots of storylines converged at <em>La Capital </em>so let's run through it.</p>
</div>
<hr class="nordic-line">
<h2 class="nordic-heading"><span style="color: #000000;">The</span> <span style="color: #ba372a;">Narratives</span></h2>
<div class="spotlight-box">
<h3 style="margin-top: 0; color: var(--nord1);">Verstappen's Historic Late Season Title Bid</h3>
<p>The biggest conversation coming into Mexico surrounded Max Verstappen and his historic late season surge to put him in contention to win his 5th title. Coming into this weekend Max Verstappen had won 3 out of the last 4 Grand Prix (Monza, Baku, and Austin) in addition to claiming a sprint victory where both McLaren drivers DNF after colliding into each other into turn one. In fact since coming out of the summer break in late August the dutchman has yet to not reach the podium in the last 6 races with 3 P1 finshes, 2 P2's and a P3 in Mexico this past weekend (sorry for the spoiler...)</p>
<figure class="post__image"><em><img loading="lazy"  src="https://clykainc.net/media/posts/6/www.formula1points.com-season-progression-2025.com-season-progression-2025-3.com season progression 2025" alt="" width="750" height="500"></figure></em></p>
<p class="align-right"><span style="color: #f1c40f;"><em>courtesy of formula1points.com</em></span></p>
<p>Max is no stranger to making the unthinkable happen, and this year is no exception. After the Dutch Grand Prix, Max handsomly sat 104 points behind the championship leader Oscar Piastri. Since that race Verstappen has outscored Oscar Piastri 116:47 and closed the gap to just 36 points the lead with just 4 races to go. </p>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  style="font-size: inherit; outline: rgba(16, 137, 255, 0.55) solid 3px !important;" src="https://clykainc.net/media/posts/6/verstappen-mexico-gp-6909a8725ae13.webp" alt="" width="750" height="500" sizes="(min-width: 1500px) calc(7.87vw + 610px), (min-width: 900px) calc(44.48vw + 68px), (min-width: 780px) calc(8vw + 604px), calc(84.35vw + 23px)" srcset="https://clykainc.net/media/posts/6/responsive/verstappen-mexico-gp-6909a8725ae13-xs.webp 300w ,https://clykainc.net/media/posts/6/responsive/verstappen-mexico-gp-6909a8725ae13-sm.webp 480w ,https://clykainc.net/media/posts/6/responsive/verstappen-mexico-gp-6909a8725ae13-md.webp 768w"></figure>
<p>After Red Bull dismissed long time team principal Christian Horner half way through the year the team all but seemed to be in an identity crisis. On the brink to giving up on this year just after the summer break, <span style="font-size: inherit;">Laurent Mekies and the engineers at Milton Keynes have done a marvelous job of steerin</span><span style="font-size: inherit;">g the team back on track as they stand just 9 points from P2 in the constructors. The team has made the executive decision to invest more time and resources into their 2025 car while teams like Williams and McLaren have since moved onto their 2026 project. Whether that will be a consequence will remain to be seen next year, but it has provided Max an oppurtunity to fight each weekend against McLaren.</span></p>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://clykainc.net/media/posts/6/20251024-0109-68fc7a62d5a50.webp" alt="" width="750" height="501" sizes="(min-width: 1500px) calc(7.87vw + 610px), (min-width: 900px) calc(44.48vw + 68px), (min-width: 780px) calc(8vw + 604px), calc(84.35vw + 23px)" srcset="https://clykainc.net/media/posts/6/responsive/20251024-0109-68fc7a62d5a50-xs.webp 300w ,https://clykainc.net/media/posts/6/responsive/20251024-0109-68fc7a62d5a50-sm.webp 480w ,https://clykainc.net/media/posts/6/responsive/20251024-0109-68fc7a62d5a50-md.webp 768w"></figure>
</div>
<div class="spotlight-box-red">
<h3 style="margin-top: 0; color: var(--nord1);">Oscar's Late Season Woes</h3>
<p>On the other end of the discussion was the concern over Oscar Piastri's recent downturn of performance. The major question lingering in the air coming into Mexico was: how would the Australian driver fair in Mexico City when the pressure of a Verstappen bid has gotten to an uncomfortable distance of becoming a reality? The driver who had been so dominate and consistent weekend after weekend through this long season has had people scratching their heads as of late.</p>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  style="outline: rgba(16, 137, 255, 0.55) solid 3px !important;" src="https://clykainc.net/media/posts/6/www.formula1points.com-season-head-to-head.com-season-head-to-head.com - season head-to-head" alt="" width="750" height="625"></figure>
<p class="align-right"><span style="color: #f1c40f;"><em>courtesy of formula1points.com</em></span></p>
<p>Excluding the outliers of Zandvoort, Baku and when Oscar gave the position back to Lando in Monza because of team orders, Norris since the British Grand Prix (Round 12) has beat his teammate 4:1 in race results. In addition, Lando also improved to tie Oscar this season after lackluster qualifying woes earlier on in the season which now reads 10:10 between the two papaya drivers. Oscar who has went on record to say that this off-season he worked on devloping his qualifying and single lap pace, has leveled the qualifying playfield against his teammate which was just 3-24 coming into this year. In an era where qualifying and clean air is king - especially for the aero on the MCL39 car, Oscar needed a big win going into Mexico.</p>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://clykainc.net/media/posts/6/8bb4cf4fc98f5ffd504013866ed6aa9201018836.webp" alt="" width="750" height="500" sizes="(min-width: 1500px) calc(7.87vw + 610px), (min-width: 900px) calc(44.48vw + 68px), (min-width: 780px) calc(8vw + 604px), calc(84.35vw + 23px)" srcset="https://clykainc.net/media/posts/6/responsive/8bb4cf4fc98f5ffd504013866ed6aa9201018836-xs.webp 300w ,https://clykainc.net/media/posts/6/responsive/8bb4cf4fc98f5ffd504013866ed6aa9201018836-sm.webp 480w ,https://clykainc.net/media/posts/6/responsive/8bb4cf4fc98f5ffd504013866ed6aa9201018836-md.webp 768w"></figure>
</div>
<div class="spotlight-box">
<h3 style="margin-top: 0; color: var(--nord1);">Fresh Faces in FP1</h3>
<p>A handful of new faces and some old faces took to the opening practice session per the F1’s rules. 9 out of the 10 teams fielded an alternative driver Friday with the exception of Sauber. <strong>Pato O Ward - McLaren, Fred Vesti - Mercedes, Antonio Fuoco - Ferrari, Arvid Lindblad, Luke Browning - Williams, Jack Crawford - Aton Martin, Ryo Hirakawa - Haas, Ayumu Iwasa - RB, Paul Aron - Alpine. </strong>Out of all the rookies, Arvid Lindblad made the best impression on paper driving hot laps on softs in the session of evolving track evolution to top all the drivers making their appearance in P6.</p>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://clykainc.net/media/posts/6/Arvid-Lindblad-Red-Bull-.webp" alt="" width="750" height="422" sizes="(min-width: 1500px) calc(7.87vw + 610px), (min-width: 900px) calc(44.48vw + 68px), (min-width: 780px) calc(8vw + 604px), calc(84.35vw + 23px)" srcset="https://clykainc.net/media/posts/6/responsive/Arvid-Lindblad-Red-Bull--xs.webp 300w ,https://clykainc.net/media/posts/6/responsive/Arvid-Lindblad-Red-Bull--sm.webp 480w ,https://clykainc.net/media/posts/6/responsive/Arvid-Lindblad-Red-Bull--md.webp 768w"></figure>
<p>Per the new 2025 changes to the rules, the FP1 requirement has expanded. Teams must now run rookies in two FP1 sessions per car, totaling four sessions across the season. Laurent Mekies made it a point to praise the 18 year old after a stressful yet successful FP1 in Max Verstappen's car.</p>
<div class="nordic-quote">
<blockquote>
<p>We took the decision to leave Arvid on low-ish fuel to not give him the complication of high and low fuel," said "He did a very good job. It's so difficult to jump in. The pace is there, so not much to argue against that.</p>
</blockquote>
<div class="author">Laurent Mekies</div>
</div>
</div>
<hr class="nordic-line">
<h2 class="nordic-heading">The Track Specifics</h2>
<div class="nordic-card">
<p>Mexic is a unique track which presents many challenges for all teams to navigate throughout the weekend. It is one of the shortest on the grid, has the longest straight down into turn one on the calendar - 830 m, and sits at the highest elevation compared to every other race. In fact, the track sits as high as 2,285 meters altitude which means that air density is 20.7% lower than that at sea level. Lower air density means less downforce, lower grip, and the car can feel on the edge throughout the entire lap. While teams would conventionally go with a low to medium drag setups on tracks such as Mexico, the inconvience of the elevated altitude means that teams have to run higher downforce configurations to prevent unsettling the car throughout the course of a lap. Pair this with expansive braking zones in the first sector—demanding pinpoint precision on entry and exit—alongside a blend of low-, medium-, and high-speed corners throughout sectors 2 and 3, and you have a track where stringing it all together poses a formidable challenge for even the top drivers. Holding pole position isn’t a guarantee through lap one either. The long straight into Turn 1 is notorious for delivering massive slipstreams to rivals tucked in behind, while a sloppy exit onto the following straight down to Turn 4 can leave you wide open to an attack. To top it all off the lower than normal down-force less air density means that both engine and brake cooling tend to be very marginal at Mexico and require additional attention between teams and their technical staff at all times.</p>
</div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
